Guide to the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files RISM.VF.1
New York University Archives
Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files
1900-2004
1960-2000
New York University Archives
Research Institute for the Study of Man
RISM.VF.1
33 Linear Feet in 32 record cartons and 2 manuscript boxes
The Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) was incorporated in 1955 to promote research on "human living throughout the world." This collection consists of publications and papers organized geographically and topically.
Scope and Contents Note
This collection is comprised mainly of RISM publications and papers organized geographically and topically.
Historical Note
The Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) was established in 1955 as a non-profit organization "to initiate and promote basic scientific research for the development and dissemination of a body of knowledge that can contribute to a better understanding of human living throughout the world." Under Vera Rubin's direction, RISM conducted research and training programs, developed a Library for Caribbean Research, organized academic conferences, provided consultation to social scientists, and supported independent research programs with applied value in the creation of public educational, medical, and social science resources.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact New York University Archives, (212) 998-2646, university-archives@nyu.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Reed Foundation.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by geographic location and subject.
Sociology -- Caribbean Area.; Anthropology -- Research.; Public health -- Caribbean Area.; Caribbean studies.; Health and race; Institute of Race Relations; Columbia University. Institute of Latin American Studies
- Africa
  - Africa: Agriculture (Box 1)
    - A Study of Hausa Domestic Economy in Northern Zaire, 1952; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 333-347. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Agriculture.
  - Africa: Civil Services (Box 1)
    - Report on Unestablished and Daily-Rated Government Servants, March 1947, RISM 24707; Nigeria. Commission on the Necessity on Consolidation of Wages; 12 pages (Box 1)
      Civil service.; Africa.
  - Africa: Civilization (Box 1)
    - Some African Problems of Today, 1951; RISM 16671; Comhaire-Sylvain, Jean; p. 15-18. (Box 1)
      Civilization.; Africa.
    - Kofi Baadu: Out of Africa, 1980; RISM 16672; Rodney, Walter Anthony, 1942-1980; 32 pages; ill. (Box 1)
    - Development Problems in Africa: An Examination of Internal Factors and the Lessons for the Caribbean, 1984; RISM 16673; Kugblenu, George; 11 pages (Box 1)
    - Report to the Carnegie Corporation of New York on Study Tour of Africa, 1961; RISM 16674; Figueroa, John J. M. (John Joseph Maria); 24 pages (Box 1)
    - The Social Functions and Meaning of Hausa Praise-Singing, 1957; RISM 17003; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 26-45. (Box 1)
  - Africa: Cults (Box 1)
    - El Culto de los Gemelos en Africa Occidental y en las Americas, undated; RISM 24218; Pollak-Eltz, Angelina; p. 65-78. (Box 1)
      Cults; Africa.
  - Africa: Dwellings (Box 1)
    - Dwellings: Foreword to Urban Housing in Africa, by Friedrich W. Schwerdtfeger, 1981; RISM 23077; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. xi-xvii.
      Dwellings.; Africa.
  - Africa: Emigration and Immigration (Box 1)
    - In Search of Social Identity: Strategies of Ethnic Identity Management Among Capeverdeans in Southeastern Massachusetts, 1976; RISM 16684; Greenfield, Sidney M.; p. 3-18. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Emigration and immigration.
    - Ethnicity and Refugees in Africa, 1981; Cultural Survival Inc. (Box 1)
  - Africa: Famine (Box 1)
    - Behind the Weather: Lessons to be Learned; Drought and Famine in Ethiopia, 1984; RISM 24398; Oxfam. Public Affairs Unit; 18 pages (Box 1)
      Africa.; Famine.
  - Africa: History (Box 1)
    - The Beginnings of Hausa Society, A.D. 1000-1500, 1964; RISM 24369; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 339-357 (Box 1)
      Africa.; History.
  - Africa: Islam (Box 1)
    - The Jihad of Shehu Dan Fodio: Some Problems, 1964; RISM 20000; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 408-424. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Islam.
  - Africa: Languages (Box 1)
    - The Tonal System of Proto-Bantu, 1948; RISM 16686; Greenberg, Joseph Harold; p. 196-208. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Languages and languages.
    - Studies in African Linguistic Classification II: The Classification of Fulani, 1949; RISM 16685; Greenberg, Joseph Harold; p. 190-198. (Box 1)
    - From Africa to the New World: The Linguistic Continuum, undated; RISM 16687; Long, Richard A., 1927-2013; 8 pages (Box 1)
  - Africa: Law (Box 1)
    - The Sociological Framework of Law, 1965; RISM 24432; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 24-48, 245-247. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Law.
  - Africa: Local Government (Box 1)
    - The Community Concept in the Study and Government of African and Afro-American Societies, 1952; RISM 20001; Comhaire-Sylvain, Jean; p. 41-48. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Local government.
  - Africa: Marriage (Box 1)
    - Secondary Marriage Among Kadara and Kagoro, 1968; RISM 20002; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 109-130. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Marriage
    - Secondary Marriage in Northern Nigeria, 1953; RISM 24964; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 298-323. (Box 1)
  - Africa: Mental Illness (Box 1)
    - Cultural Definitions of Illness: Social Psychiatry Views Intercultural and Inter-Class Communication in Ghana, 1963; RISM 20003; Opler, Marvin K. (Marvin Kaufmann), 1914-1981; p. 446-473. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Mental illness.
  - Africa: Names (Box 1)
    - African Names Book: From Those Home to Those Abroad, undated; RISM 23030; unpaged. (Box 1)
      Africa.; Names.
  - Africa: Poetry (Box 1)
    - The Mission of the Poet, undated; RISM 16030; Senghor, L‌eopold S‌edar, 1906-2001; 10 pages (Box 1)
      Africa.; Poetry.
  - Africa: Politics and Government (Box 1)
    - Why Seperation of Power Will Preserve Peace, 1977; Rhoodie, Eschel M. (Eschel Mostert); 2 pages (Box 1)
      Africa.; Politics and government.
  - Africa: Rastafarians (Box 1)
    - The Baye Faal of Senegambia: Muslim Rastas in the Promised Land?, 1994; RISM 20004; Savishinsky, Neil J.; p. 211-219. (Box 1)
      Rastafari movement.; Africa.
  - Africa: Religious Cults (Box 1)
    - Le Culte des Marassas, 1945; RISM 23078; Price-Mars, Jean, 1876-1969; p. 41-49. (Box 1)
  - Africa: Sierra Leone, Economic Conditions (Box 1)
    - Sierra Leone: Ten Years of Independence, 1961-1971, ca. 1971; RISM 23079; Sierra Leone. Government Information Services; 53 pages (Box 1)
      Sierra Leone.; Economic conditions.; Africa.
  - Africa: Slave Trade (Box 1)
    - West Africa and the Atlantic Slave-Trade, 1967; RISM 20005; Rodney, Walter Anthony, 1942-1980; 28 pages (Box 1)
      Africa.; Slave trade.
    - Survivors of the Middle Passage: Life Histories of Enslaved Africans in British America, 2002; RISM 27118; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 25-56. (Box 1)
      Slave trade.; Africa.
  - Africa: Social Classes (Box 1)
    - Kebbi and Hausa Stratification, 1961; RISM 24447; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 52-64. (Box 1)
      Social classes.; Africa.
- Anguilla (Box 1)
  - Anguilla: Agriculture (Box 1)
    - Annual Report of the Department of Agriculture and Fisheries, 1983-1984; audience="internal" RISM 7465; Anguilla. Agriculture & Fisheries Department; 2 items; no content (Box 1)
      Anguilla; Agriculture.
  - Anguilla: Autonomy (Box 1)
    - Anguilla: U.D.I. or Not?, 1969; RISM 16780; McDonald, Frank; 7 pages (Box 1)
      Autonomy.; Anguilla
    - Anguilla: A New Constitution and the Declaration of Independence, 1969; RISM 16899; McDonald, Frank; 15 pages (Box 1)
      Anguilla; Autonomy.
    - Anguilla: Independence 1967-69 and Some Important Reactions, 1969; RISM 16900; McDonald, Frank; 7 pages (Box 1)
    - Anguilla's Tradition of Independence, 1969; RISM 16901; Harris, David; p. 643-648. (Box 1)
    - Fourth Committee Discusses Gibralter; Hears Petitioners on Anguilla, 1967; RISM 23210; United Nations. General Assembly. Fourth Committee; various paging. (Box 1)
  - Anguilla: Description and Travel (Box 1)
    - Anguilla: The Basic Facts, 1979; RISM 16777; Anguilla. Central Office of Information; 24 pages; ill. (Box 1)
      Anguilla
    - Anguilla: Returning a Year Later, 1968; RISM 16776; McDonald, Frank; 6 pages (Box 1)
    - Anguilla, West Indies: A Visitor's Guide, undated; RISM 16779; Anguilla. Department of Tourism; unpaged (Box 1)
    - Anguilla, West Indies: Where the Caribbean Smiles, undated; RISM 20006; Anguilla. Department of Tourism; 10 pages (Box 1)
    - Anguilla; Overseas Territory of the UK, 2000; RISM 26324; 6 pages; 6.0 (Box 1)
  - Anguilla: Drug Trade (Box 1)
    - Judicial Assistance: Narcotics Activities in Anguilla; Agreement Effected by Exchange of Letters, 1989; RISM 17901; United States. Department of State; 21 pages (Box 1)
      Anguilla; Drug traffic.
  - Anguilla: Economic Conditions (Box 1)
    - Government of Anguilla: Tourism Policy No. 2, 1985; RISM 16763 (Box 1)
      Economic conditions.; Anguilla
  - Anguilla: Emigration and Immigration (Box 1)
    - Government of Anguilla: Immigration and Labour Policy, 1990; RISM 16465; 6 pages (Box 1)
      Emigration and immigration.; Anguilla
  - Anguilla: Family (Box 1)
    - Family and Social Structure in Anguilla, 1968; RISM 18414; Walker, Della M.; p. 111-116. (Box 1)
      Family.; Anguilla
  - Anguilla: History (Box 1)
    - Letter from Anguilla, June 1968; RISM 17001; Updike, John; p. 70-80. (Box 1)
      History.; Anguilla
  - Anguilla: Politics and Government (Box 1)
    - Anguilla: Operation Sheepskin, 1969; RISM 16775; McDonald, Frank; 36 pages (Box 1)
      Politics and government.; Anguilla
    - United Nations: Anguilla, 1968; RISM 16778; McDonald, Frank; 8 pages (Box 1)
    - Anguilla: Decisions of the House of Assembly on the Report of the Constitution Review Committee, 1988; RISM 16781; Anguilla. Constitution Review Committee; 8 pages (Box 1)
    - Their's Not to Reason Why: A Study of the Anguillan Operation as Presented to Parliament, 1969; RISM 16782; Marten, Neil; 22 pages (Box 1)
    - Political Disintegration: The Lessons of Anguilla, 1971; RISM 16783; p. 58-74. (Box 1)
      Anguilla; Politics and government.
    - Report of Commonwealth Conference on Anguilla, 1967; RISM 16784; 30 pages (Box 1)
    - The Anguilla (Temporary Provision) Order, 1969, RISM 16785; Great Britain. Colonial Office; 2 pages (Box 1)
    - Political Fragmentation in the Caribbean: The Case of Anguilla, 1971; RISM 16786; Clarke, Colin G.; p. 15-29. (Box 1)
    - Anguilla: Crisis in the Caribbean, 1969; RISM 16787; McDonald, Frank; 12 pages (Box 1)
    - Prepared Statement of Mr. Roger Fisher, Petitioner, on behalf of Anguilla, before the United Nations Fourth Committee, December 8, 1967, RISM 16788; Fisher, Roger; 7 pages (Box 1)
    - In Anguilla It's the Spirit of '71, 1971; RISM 16789; Westlake, Donald E.; p. 25, 76-79. (Box 1)
    - The Anguillan Crisis, 1968; RISM 16790; Sherlock, Ann; 21 pages (Box 1)
    - Message to the People of Anguilla from the British Government, undated; RISM 17002; 34 pages (Box 1)
      Politics and government.; Anguilla; Great Britain.
  - Anguilla: Solar Stills (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Anguilla Solar Still Project, 1968; RISM 20007; Thierstein, Gerald E.; 9 pages; p. 1-9. (Box 1)
      Solar stills.; Anguilla
  - Anguilla: Statistics (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Report of the Mission to Anguilla on the Improvement of the Statistical Unit, 31 March-4 April 1986, RISM 24934; Harding, Lawrence Abayomi Wilfred; unpaged. (Box 1)
      Statistics.; Anguilla
  - Anguilla: Tourism (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Tourism Statistics, 1977-1986, 1987; RISM 16545; Anguilla. Statistical Branch. Development & Planning Unit; unpaged (Box 1)
      Tourism.; Anguilla
    - Annual Report of the Department of Tourism, 1984-1986; RISM 4519; Anguilla. Department of Tourism; 2 items; no content (Box 1)
    - Government of Anguilla: Draft Tourism Policy, 1978; RISM 20008; Anguilla. Ministry of Natural Resources and Tourism; 12 pages (Box 1)
    - Government of Anguilla Tourism Policy, 1985; RISM 20009; Anguilla. Ministry of Natural Resources and Tourism; 7 pages (Box 1)
    - Anguilla: Tourism and Travel Statistics, 1980-1986, 1987; RISM 20010; Anguilla. Statistical Branch. Development & Planning Unit; 15 pages (Box 1)
- Antigua and Barbuda (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda (Box 1)
    - Island Orphans: Barbuda and the Rest, 1980; RISM 16958; Lowenthal, David; p. 293-307. (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.
    - The Social and Economic Role of Cattle in Barbuda, 1977; RISM 16960; Berleant-Schiller, Riva; p. 299-309. (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Agriculture (Box 1)
    - Antigua Peasant Agriculture, 1956; RISM 24372; George, Mc.; p. 264-266. (Box 1)
      Agriculture.; Antigua and Barbuda.
    - Peasant Agricuture in Antigua, 1955; RISM 24373; Brown, F. A.; 9 pages (Box 1)
    - Summary of Industrial Development, 1945; RISM 24374; p. 10-13. (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Airlines (Box 1)
    Airlines |z Antigua and Barbuda.
    - Aviation: Transport Services; Agreement Between the United States of American and Antigua and Barbuda, Modifying Agreement of July 23, 1977, 1991; RISM 16769; United States. Department of State; 4.0 (Box 1)
      Airlines.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Amateur Radio Stations (Box 1)
    - Telecommunications; Radio Communications Between Amateur Stations on Behalf of Third Parties, Arrangement Between United States of America and Antigua and Barbuda, 1985; RISM 16774; United States. Department of State; 5 pages (Box 1)
      Amateur radio stations; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Archaeology (Box 1)
    - The First Siboney Sites of Antigua Threatened, 1982; RISM 16840; Nicholson, Desmond V.; 2 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Archaeology.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Banks and Banking (Box 1)
    - Antigua Commercial Bank: Annual Report, 1986; RISM 20012; Antigua Commercial Bank; 28 pages (Box 1)
      Banks and banking.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Bibliography (Box 1)
    - The Road to Independence: Antigua & Barbuda; A Select Bibliography, 1981; RISM 16805; Callender, Jean A.; 16 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Bibliography.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Carnival (Box 1)
    - Carnival in Antigua: An Indigenous Festival in a Tourist Economy, 1978; RISM 17520; Manning, Frank E.; p. 191-204. (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Carnival.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Church History (Box 1)
    - A Brief History of the Parish of St. Philip, with St. Stephen, Antigua, British West Indies, 1939; RISM 17074; Goodwin, Doreen; 17 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Church history.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Constitutional History (Box 1)
    - Report of the Antigua Constitutional Conference, 1966; RISM 16816; 22 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Constitutional history.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Description and Travel (Box 1)
    - A Reporter at Large; Barbuda, 1989; RISM 16806; Coram, Robert; p. 76-94. (Box 1)
    - Background Notes: Antigua and Barbuda, 1985-2000; RISM 16807; United States. Department of State. Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs; 4 items; no content (Box 1)
    - Notes on Conditions: Antigua; An Outline Guide for Expatriate Contract Employees, 1973; RISM 16808; Royal Commonwealth Society. Library; 19 pages (Box 1)
    - Fort George, Monks Hill, Antigua, undated; RISM 16809; Nicholson, Desmond V.; unpaged (Box 1)
    - Changing Cultural Landscapes in Antigua, British West Indies, 1954; RISM 16810; Crist, Raymond E.; p. 225-232 (Box 1)
    - Antigua and Barbuda, 2000; RISM 26325; 7 pages; 7.0 (Box 1)
    - Where to Stay in Antigua, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Antigua, A Bustling, British Island, 1990; 4 pages (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Economic Assistance (Box 1)
    - Economic: Technical and Related Assistance; Agreement Between the United States and Antigua and Barbuda, 1985; RISM 17913; United States. Department of State; 5 pages (Box 1)
      Economic assistance.; Antigua and Barbuda.
    - The Failure of Agricultural Development in Post-Emancipation Barbuda: A Study of Social and Economic Continuity in a West Indian Community, 1978; RISM 16959; Berleant-Schiller, Riva; p. 21-36. (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Economic Conditions (Box 1)
    - Investing in Antigua and Barbuda, 1986; RISM 16811; Caribbean/Central American Action (Organization); 16 pages (Box 1)
      Economic conditions.; Antigua and Barbuda.
    - Economic Tribulations in the Caribbean: A Case Study in the British West Indies, 1955; RISM 16812; Lowenthal, David; p. 67-81. (Box 1)
    - Antigua Sheds Grant-Aided Status, 1963; RISM 16813; Richards, Novelle H.; p. 5. (Box 1)
    - The Economy of Antigua, 1951; RISM 24612; Rottenberg, Simon; p. 851-855. (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Fishing (Box 1)
    - Environment, Technology and the Catch: Fishing and Lobster-Diving in Barbuda, Nov. 3, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Land Tenure (Box 1)
    - Patterns and Problems of Land Tenure in the Lesser Antilles: Antigua, British West Indies, 1953; RISM 20013; Augelli, John P.; p. 362-367. (Box 1)
      Land tenure.; Antigua and Barbuda.
    - Antigua Land Settlement and Development Board: Annual Report for 1947, RISM 20014; Antigua. Land Settlement and Development Board; 17 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Land tenure.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Military Assistance, American (Box 1)
    - Peacekeeping; Agreement Between the United States of America and Antigua and Barbuda, 1984; RISM 20015; United States. Department of State; 4 pages (Box 1)
      Military assistance American.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Military Bases, American (Box 1)
    - Defense Bases: Agreement Between the United States of America and Antigua and Barbuda, 1986; RISM 20016; United States. Department of State; 5 pages (Box 1)
      Military bases, American; Antigua and Barbuda.
    - Defense Areas and Facilities: Agreement Between the United States of America and Antigua, 1977; RISM 20017; United States. Department of State; 24 pages (Box 1)
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Military Education (Box 1)
    - Defense: International Military Education and Training (IMET); Agreement Between the United States of America and Antigua and Barbuda, 1981; RISM 20018; United States. Department of State; 3 pages (Box 1)
      Military education.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Peasantry (Box 1)
    - Production and Division of Labor in a West Indian Peasant Community, 1977; RISM 20019; Berleant-Schiller, Riva; p. 253-272. (Box 1)
      Peasants.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Plantations (Box 1)
    - The Rise of a Colonial Gentry: A Case Study of Antigua, 1730-1775, 1961; RISM 24480; Sheridan, Richard B.; p. 342-357. (Box 1)
      Plantations.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Politics and Government (Box 1)
    - A Short History of the Heads of Government of the Island of Antigua, The West Indies, 1962; RISM 10012; Harper, Bessie; 24 pages (Box 1)
      Politics and government.; Antigua and Barbuda.
    - The Decline of Egalitarianism in Antiguan Politics, 1981; RISM 16817; Carmody, Caroline M.; 17 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Politics and government.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Pottery (Box 1)
    - Notes on Pottery-Making in Antigua, 1964; RISM 12338; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 150-151. (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Pottery.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Public Health (Box 1)
    - Antigua Medical and Health Department: Annual Medical and Sanitary Report, 1958-1960; RISM 20020; Antigua. Medical Department; 2 items; 1958, 1960; no content (Box 1)
      Public health.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Skin Diving (Box 1)
    - Skin Diving in Antigua and Barbuda (For the Beginner), 1968; RISM 20023; Westcott, L. H. C. (Lee Harris Camacho), 1929-; 10 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Skin diving.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Social Classes (Box 1)
    - From Free Colored to Middle Class: The Development of a Segment of the Population in the British West Indies, 1979; RISM 20436; Lowes, Susan; 12 pages (Box 1)
      Social classes.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Soils (Box 1)
    - The Sugar-Cane Soils of Antigua, 1933; RISM 20022; Hardy, F.; 34 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Soils.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Telecommunication (Box 1)
    - Exchange of Notes: Between the Government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland and the United States of America Concerning the Establishment of a Station for Space Vehicle Tracking and Communications on Antigua, 1967; RISM 23481; Great Britain. Colonial Office; 8 pages (Box 1)
      Telecommunication.; Antigua and Barbuda.
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Trade Unions (Box 1)
    - Antigua Trades & Labour Union: 53rd Anniversary Celebration and Presentation of Certificates of Awards, 1992; RISM 20024; Antigua Trades and Labour Union; 8 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Labor unions
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Trade Unions, Political Activity (Box 1)
    - Politics and Trade Unions: An Antiguan Case Study, 1969; RISM 20025; Makiesky-Barrow, Susan R.; 16 pages (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Labor unions; Political participation
  - Antigua and Barbuda: Women (Box 1)
    - Information on the Women's Desk: Antigua & Barbuda 1980-1986, 1987; RISM 20026; Antigua and Barbuda. Women's Desk; unpaged. (Box 1)
      Antigua and Barbuda.; Women.
    - The Women's Desk, Antigua and Barbuda: Unity for Development, Plan of Action, 1987-1990, 1988; RISM 20027; Antigua and Barbuda. Ministry of Education, Culture, Youth, Women's Affairs & Sports; unpaged. (Box 1)
- Aruba (Box 1)
  - Aruba: Agricultural Industries (Box 1)
    - Aloe Cultivation and Industrialization of Aruba: A Symbolic Interlude, 1980; RISM 24205; Phalen, John Harvey; p. 52-65. (Box 1)
      Agricultural industries.; Aruba
  - Aruba: Autonomy (Box 1)
    - Aruba en de Separacion, 1955; RISM 20028; Heald, Henry T. (Henry Townley), 1904-1975; p. 113-134. (Box 1)
      Aruba; Autonomy.
  - Aruba: Description and Travel (Box 1)
    - Aruba; Kingdom of The Netherlands, 2000; RISM 26326; 7 pages; 7.0 (Box 1)
      Aruba
    - Aruba, Netherlands Antilles: Only Six Hours By Plane From Miami, undated (Box 1)
  - Aruba: Economic Conditions (Box 1)
    - Investing in Aruba, 1986; RISM 16999; Caribbean/Central American Action (Organization); 15 pages (Box 1)
      Aruba; Economic conditions.
  - Aruba: Family (Box 1)
    - Methodological Problems Involved in the Study of the Aruban Family, 1969; RISM 18415; Green, Vera M.; p. 17-22. (Box 1)
      Aruba; Family.
  - Aruba: Kinship (Box 1)
    - Some Aspects of Reciprocal Exchange: Economic Organization in Aruba (Netherlands Antilles), 1980; RISM 24206; Phalen, John Harvey; p. 620-625. (Box 1)
      Kinship.; Aruba
- Asia (Box 1)
  - Asia: Intercultural Education (Box 1)
    - The International Significance of Asia and the Far East from the Intellectual and Cultural Standpoint, 1974; RISM 20029; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; 44 pages (Box 1)
      Multicultural education.; Asia.
- Bahamas (Box 1)
  - Bahamas: Autonomy (Box 1)
    - On Becoming an Independent Nation: An Interview with the Hon. Lynden O. Pindling, Prime Minister of the Bahamas, ca. 1973; RISM 16903; Gordon, Carlton; p. 24-29. (Box 1)
      Bahamas.; Autonomy.
  - Bahamas: Bibliography (Box 1)
    - An Annotated, Ethnographic Bibliography of the Bahama Islands, 1976; RISM 24097; LaFlamme, Alan G.; p. 57-67. (Box 1)
      Bibliography.; Bahamas.
  - Bahamas: Constitutional History (Box 1)